Guide to the Bicentennial Committee for International Conferences of Americanists Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bicentennial Committee for International Conferences of Americanists records
1973-1977
RU 152
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.5
(16 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence and topical files maintained by Robin Winks as coordinator of the Bicentennial Committee for International Conferences of Americanists.
Bicentennial Committee for International Conferences of Americanists
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 50 (YRG 50), Records of conferences and symposia at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence and topical files maintained by Robin Winks as coordinator of the Bicentennial Committee for International Conferences of Americanists.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Congresses and conventions; Meetings; United States -- Civilization -- Congresses; United States -- Civilization -- Foreign influences -- Congresses; Winks, Robin W., 1930-; Bicentennial Committee for International Conferences of Americanists
- Records of the Bicentennial Committee for International Conferences of Americanists, 1973-1977; Series I
  - Conferences
    - American Studies Conference: meetings, 1976 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - African Regional Conference on American Studies (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
    - European Regional Conference: publications (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - European Regional Conference: programs, participants, etc. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Japanese Conference: participants, etc. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Japanese Conference: publications (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Japanese Conference: publications (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - NAMESA Conference: publications (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - NAMESA Conference: programs, participants, etc. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - New World Conference: publications (Box 2, Folder 11 - 13)
    - New World Conference: programs, participants, etc. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Toqueville Conference (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Regional Publications and Greenwood Contracts (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Washington Conference, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Statement of America Abroad (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Planning of Conferences (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Media (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence
    - African Conference (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Belmont Conference (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - invitations, responses, 1976 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - invitations, responses, 1976 August 16 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - letters, responses, 1976 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - follow-up letter to acceptances (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - alternates (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - invitation, old and new versions (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Belmont Center: enclosures and data (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - European Regional Conference, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - European Regional Conference: evaluations (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Far Eastern Regional Conference (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Middle East Conference (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - NAMESA: cables (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - New World Conference (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Bicentennial Committee: lists, 1974 November (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Bicentennial Committee: articles (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Bicentennial Committee: meeting minutes (Box 5, Folder 38 - 39)
    - Forrey, Robert
      - 1973 Sep - 1974 Jun (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - 1974 Jul - Dec (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - 1975 Jan - Apr (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - 1975 May - Aug (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - 1975 Sep - Dec (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - 1976 (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - 1976 Aug 27 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - 1974 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - 1974 Nov (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Forrey, Robert: interoffice memo, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Winks, Robin
      - 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - 1975 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Winks, Robin: outgoing, 1973 December - 1975 October (Box 7)
    - Winks, Robin: incoming, 1973 October - 1976 August (Box 7)
    - Winks, Robin, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - Winks, Robin: outgoing, 1975 October - 1976 September (Box 7)
    - Addresses: Foreign/Fulbright (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Afro-American Studies (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Albany (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - American Housing Association (AHA) (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - American Studies: Allen Davis (Box 8, Folder 64 - 65)
    - American Studies: ASA and ACLS (Box 8, Folder 66 - 67)
    - Allen Davis and Richard Downer (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - American Studies: Iran (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Americanists: foreign, natural (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - American Revolution Bicentennial Association (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Arndt, Richard T. (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Association Exam Board (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Bailyn Paper (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Belgium Report (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Bibliographies (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Binet (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Book displays (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Brazil (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Confederate of American Studies (CASA) (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Contact offices (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - CASA - Arthur Dudden (Seville) (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Dillon, Wilton S. (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Directory: International (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - Douglass, Ann (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - Dudden, Arthur (Box 9, Folder 86)
    - Espindoza and Clifton (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - European Association for American Studies (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Exchange Article: Robert Forrey/Robert Winks (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - Exchange Jahanpour Article (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - Exchange (Cultural) Program (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - Field messages (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Foreign participants (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - General conference (Box 9, Folder 94 - 97)
    - Giliomee and CG memo (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - Greenwood Press (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - Hague, John A.: Director of American Studies Association (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Jacobs, Rita (Box 10, Folder 101)
    - Lashly, Jean (Box 10, Folder 102)
    - Magazines: Center for Health (Box 10, Folder 103)
    - Minnich, Arthur (Box 10, Folder 104)
    - National Humanities Institute (Box 10, Folder 105)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grant (Box 10, Folder 106 - 107)
    - Pearson, Norman (Box 10, Folder 108)
    - Purchase requisitions (Box 10, Folder 109)
    - Ritcheson, Charles (Box 10, Folder 110)
    - Rice, Richard (Box 10, Folder 111)
    - Richard, John (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - Rose, Peter (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - Roth, Richard L. (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - State Dept. Grant Printout, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 115)
    - Strauss, Richard (Box 10, Folder 116)
    - Travel and Reimbursement, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 117 - 119)
    - Vital Issues (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - Walker, Robert (Box 11, Folder 121 - 122)
    - "Yale and the Bicentennial" (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - International Events
    - American Studies (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - 125 Argentina (Box 11, Folder 125)
    - Australia (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - Austria (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - Belgium (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Blue, William L. (Box 12, Folder 129)
    - Boorstien, Daniel (Box 12, Folder 130)
    - Canada (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - China (Box 12, Folder 132)
    - Chisolm, Larry (Box 12, Folder 133)
    - Clifton, Ron (Box 12, Folder 134)
    - Denmark (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - Finland (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - France (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - Fulbright (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - Germany (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Goetzman, William (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Greece (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - India (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - Ireland (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - Italy (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - Japan (Box 13, Folder 145)
    - Japan (Box 13, Folder 146)
    - Japan: Kinuko Kubota (Box 13, Folder 147)
    - Japan: Dick Underwood (Box 13, Folder 148)
    - Japan: American Grantee (Box 13, Folder 149)
    - Korea (Box 13, Folder 150)
    - Lagos (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - Lagos: correspondence (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - Lagos: Letitia Brown (Box 13, Folder 153)
    - Netherlands (Box 13, Folder 154)
    - New World: correspondence (Box 13, Folder 155)
    - New World: San Antonio (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - Norway: American Studies (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - Panama: Bicentennial (Box 14, Folder 158 - 159)
    - Poland (Box 14, Folder 160)
    - Portugal (Box 14, Folder 161)
    - Poster: National Trust Fund for Historic Prevention (Box 14, Folder 162)
    - Salzburg: information (Box 14, Folder 163 - 164)
    - Salzburg: correspondence (Box 14, Folder 165 - 166)
    - Salzburg: Arthur Glover (Box 14, Folder 167)
    - South Africa (Box 14, Folder 168)
    - Spain (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - Sweden (Box 14, Folder 170)
    - Switzerland (Box 14, Folder 171)
    - Tehran: correspondence (Box 15, Folder 172)
    - Tehran (Box 15, Folder 173 - 174)
    - Tulchin (Box 15, Folder 175)
    - Turkey (Box 15, Folder 176)
    - Venezuela (Box 15, Folder 177 - 178)
    - Virgin Islands (Box 15, Folder 179)
    - Yugoslavia (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Financial Papers
    - Robin Winks - Budget Printouts, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 181 - 182)
  - Reports
    - Robin Winks: "An American Guide to Britain" (Box 16, Folder 183 - 185)
    - Bicentennial Annual Report (Box 16, Folder 186)